...No...
（鮮血(せんけつ)）やめろ やめてくれ
...Please...
Don't!
やめろ！
（流子(りゅうこ)）ハッ！
Senketsu!
鮮血！
Good grief.
（美木杉(みきすぎ)）やれやれ
僕は何回 気絶した君を
介抱したらいいんだろうね
How many times will I have to
take care of you after you've passed out?
Did you decide to change careers and become a Nudist like me?
（美木杉）君もヌーディストに
くら替えかい？
Make one more lame joke
and it'll be your last.
（流子）今 下手な冗談
言うと殺すぞ
Ah, sorry, sorry.
So, who took you out?
（美木杉）ああ ごめんごめん
誰にやられた？
It was Harime Nui. Nagita was Nui.
針目縫(はりめぬい)だ　凪田(なぎた)は縫だった
（美木杉）そういうことか
Oh, so that's what happened.
You found me unconscious,
dressed like this?
私はこの姿で気絶してたのか？
Yeah. If I had arrived
on the scene a little later,
（美木杉）
ああ 僕が駆けつけるのが
もう少し遅かったら—
you would've been arrested
by the cops for indecent exposure.
露出狂として
警察に保護されてただろうね
You got a death wish?
（流子）死にたいのか？
（美木杉）荒れてるね
Touchy, aren't we?
...Of course I am. I...
（流子）当ったり前だ
あたしは… あたしは鮮血を失った
I lost Senketsu.
To Harime Nui?
（美木杉）針目縫にかな？
That's right. He was
chopped to pieces by her.
そうだ あいつに切り刻まれた
I was weak and I couldn't draw upon
...any of his power, and he got shredded...
あたしが弱かったばっかりに
鮮血の力も出せずバラバラに…
I am not lost.
（鮮血）失ってはいない
（流子）ん？
Any more lame impressions like that
and I really am gonna kill you.
（流子）
下手な声マネなんかすると
本当に殺すぞ
Hey, give me a break.
I didn't say anything.
（美木杉）
おいおい勘弁してくれよ
僕は何にもしてはいない
（鮮血）流子 落ち着け
（流子）ハッ
Ryuuko, calm yourself.
（流子）ほら また！
See, you're doing it again!
I have him right here.
彼なら ここだよ
Senketsu, you're alive?! I'm so glad!
鮮血 生きてたのか！ よかった
（鮮血）流子がしっかり
握っていてくれていたからな
Only because you
held on to me so tightly.
And the rest?
Where's the rest of you?
（流子）ほかは？
ほかはどうした？
The sleeves? The shoulders? The skirt?
袖や胴やスカートは？
あ… あれ？
H-Huh?
（美木杉）
僕が駆けつけたときには
見当たらなかった
I didn't see anything else
when I got there.
Just you, lying there unconscious,
clutching that scarf like your life depended on it.
ただ そのスカーフだけを
握りしめて君は倒れていたんだ
Ryuuko, my shredded body has been
divided amongst the Battlefield Trip students.
（鮮血）流子
私のバラバラになった体は—
襲学(しゅうがく)旅行の生徒に配られた
じゃあ残りは関西か
So the rest of you is in Kansai, huh?
（鮮血）そういうことだ
鬼龍院皐月(きりゅういんさつき)の仕業だ
Exactly. It was Kiryuuin Satsuki's doing.
Damn her.
She's always getting in my way!
皐月め ふざけやがって！
Huh? What's a teacher like you
doing here, Mr. Mikisugi?
（又郎(またろう)）あれ？
美木杉先生 何やってんの？
残念ながら
もう先生ではないのだよ
Sorry to say, but I am
no longer a teacher.
The time has now come.
時ここに満ちたり
Today, I bid farewell to my cover identity as the
homeroom teacher for Honnouji Academy's Class 2-A.
本能字(ほんのうじ)学園２年甲組
担任の姿とは今日でお別れだ
Today, I return to my unadorned self!
今日からは裸の自分を取り戻す
As one of the unclothed warriors of Nudist Beach
who do battle against the threat of Life Fibers:
そう 生命戦維(せんい)の脅威と戦う
裸の戦士たち
a Splendid Naked Officer,
ヌーディスト･ビーチの—
スプレンディッド･
ネイキッドオフィサー…
Mikisugi Aikurou! Let's begin!
NUDIST BEACH SPLENDID
NAKED OFFICER
MIKISUGI
AIKUROU
レッツ ビギン！
Come on, Nude Shooting Star!
カモン！ 裸の流星号
さらばだ
Farewell, students of Honnouji Academy!
本能字学園の諸君！
What the hell was that about?
何なんだ ありゃ
EPISODE 14
RIDE LIKE THE WIND
This is a world tailored to someone's whims and fancies
dareka ga katteni kimeta readymade na
I'll break free of its shackles
kyou wo nugisutete
RYUUKO
MATOI
And sprint toward my goal
hadashi de hashitte iku
Even if I lose my way
machigattatte
GAMAGOORI IRA
SANAGEYAMA UZU
JAKUZURE NONON
INUMUTA HOUKA
Or trip and fall
korondatte
INUMUTA HOUKA
MANKANSHOKU FAMILY
Those wounds will still create
surimuita itami mo
MANKANSHOKU
MAKO
MIKISUGI
AIKUROU
KINAGASE
TSUMUGU
An original future for me
original na ashita ni naru
KIRYUUIN
SATSUKI
I hold my destiny in my own hands
tsukiageta kono te ni nigirishimeta
And it shines ever so brightly
chikai ga hikari ni natte
So until the day I reach you
itsuka kimi ni todoku sono shunkan made
I don't have the time to sit around crying
naiteru hima nante nai kara
My burning passion pours out from within me
hamidashite shimatta atsui omoi ga
And shines like a star in the night sky
yozora de kagayaki dasu
I think I now understand
umarete kita imi ga
Why I was born
wakatta ki ga shita
I'll make all of my dreams come true
negaigoto wa zenbu kono te de
With my own hands
kanaeru
（伊織(いおり)）生命戦維耐性の強い
生徒をチョイスし—
I have selected students
with high Life Fiber tolerance,
and I am distributing the various parts
of Godrobe Senketsu amongst them.
神衣(かむい)鮮血の各パーツを
配布しています
They will be affixed to their
Battlefield Trip-spec Ultima Uniforms,
襲学旅行用極(ごく)制服に装着し
それぞれの能力の—
and I will ascertain whether they can be employed
as a power-up item that will boost their abilities.
パワーアップアイテムとして
使用できるかを実戦で確認します
Good.
（皐月）うむ
（受信音）
KYOTO
The Kyoto Battlefield Trip Brigade
under Jakuzure Nonon,
（スピーカー:男性）
蛇崩乃音(じゃくずれののん)率いる京都制圧襲学旅団
KOBE
the Kobe Battlefield Trip Brigade
under Gamagoori Ira
蟇郡苛(がまごおりいら)率いる神戸制圧襲学旅団
and the Osaka Battlefield Trip Brigade
under Sanageyama Uzu
OSAKA
猿投山渦(さなげやまうず)率いる大阪制圧襲学旅団
それぞれ目的地に到着しました
have each arrived at their
respective destinations.
BIG THREE CITIES
SPECIAL INTELLIGENCE
UNIT
INUMUTA
HOUKA
（犬牟田(いぬむた)）
三都情報撹乱(かくらん)部隊も準備完了
The Big Three Cities Special
Intelligence Unit also stands ready.
We've already seized the information
gateways for each city's academies.
各学園の情報網は掌握済み
Their information networks have been isolated,
（スピーカー:犬牟田）
彼らの情報ネットワークは
分断され—
and all phone and net connections
are under our control.
電話もネットも全て
こちらの管理下に置かれています
Good.
よし この作戦に成功して
関西の高校を一気に傘下に収める
This operation will place all of Kansai's
high schools under our umbrella in one fell swoop.
BIG THREE BATTLEFIELD TRIP
Big Three Battlefield Trip,
commence operation!
作戦開始！
Kami-Kobe High School Armed Faction
Alliance Representative, Oobayashi Kyuuji!
（大林(おおばやし)）神(かみ)神戸高校
武闘派連合総代…
KAMI-KOBE HIGH
SCHOOL ARMED
ACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
OOBAYASHI
KYUUJI
KAMI-KOBE HIGH
SCHOOL ARMED
ACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
OOBAYASHI
KYUUJI
KAMI-KOBE HIGH
SCHOOL ARMED
ACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
OOBAYASHI
KYUUJI
KAMI-KOBE HIGH
SCHOOL ARMED
ACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
OOBAYASHI
KYUUJI
KAMI-KOBE HIGH
SCHOOL ARMED
ACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
OOBAYASHI
KYUUJI
Deputy Armed Faction
Alliance Representative, Sakuramiya Kenta!
（桜宮(さくらみや)）同じく副総代…
DEPUTY ARMED
FACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
SAKURAMIYA
KENTA
DEPUTY ARMED
FACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
SAKURAMIYA
KENTA
DEPUTY ARMED
FACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
SAKURAMIYA
KENTA
DEPUTY ARMED
FACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
SAKURAMIYA
KENTA
DEPUTY ARMED
FACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
SAKURAMIYA
KENTA
DEPUTY ARMED
FACTION ALLIANCE
REPRESENTATIVE
ここから先は一歩も通さんで
火炎瓶いったれや！
We won't let them take a
single step beyond this point!
Molotov cocktails! Cut loose!
（神神戸高校生徒たち）そりゃ〜！
We got help from the
American school, too!
（桜宮）
アメリカンハイスクールからも
助っ人(と)や
武装アメフト軍団のパワーで
蹴散らしたるわい！
We'll drive 'em out with the power of
their Armed American Football Corps!
I am Gamagoori Ira, Honnouji Academy
Battlefield Trip Kobe Region Brigade Leader!
（蟇郡）本能字学園
三都制圧襲学旅行…
BATTLEFIELD
TRIP KOBE
REGION
BRIGADE
LEADER
GAMAGOORI
IRA
If you engage in armed resistance,
we are prepared to retaliate in kind!
貴君らが武力抵抗するのならば
我らにも撃つ用意あり
Enhanced Disciplinary
Bureau Members, deploy!
強化風紀委員 散開！
What the hell?
何やそれ この装甲プロテクターの
餌食にしたるわ
Your blood will nourish
our armored protective gear!
All hands, charge!
全員突撃！
（アメフト部員たち）レッツゴー！
Let's go!
Fire!
（蟇郡）てい！
（風紀委員たち）よ〜し！
Oh my God!
（アメフト部員たち）
オーマイガー！
...What the...?!
何！
To a student, school regulations
are heavier than stone!
学生にとって校則は岩より重し
The Disciplinary Guidebook in which
these rules are inscribed is harder than steel!
その本文の記せし生徒手帳は
鉄より固し
Honnouji Academy
Disciplinary Guidebook
Honnouji Academy's
school regulations are as steel!
本能字学園の校則こそ
いわば“鋼” 鋼の規則
Honnouji Academy
Disciplinary Guidebook
Ironclad rules!
Honnouji Academy
Disciplinary Guidebook
Do you believe that such armor
can withstand our ironclad rules?!
その程度の装甲で
我らの校則が防げるか！
Taste our Full Metal Disciplinary
Guidebook Regulation Hurricane!
食らえ！
FULL METAL DISCIPLINARY - GUIDEBOOK REGULATION HURRICANE
（風紀委員たち）帳！　帳！
I-Impossible!
ア… アホな…
Do you see now the might
of Honnouji Academy?!
（蟇郡）
見たか！ これが本能字学園の力
我らが生徒会長
This is the might of Student Council
President Kiryuuin Satsuki!
鬼龍院皐月様の力だ！
Let's play this fortissimo, everyone!
（蛇崩）みんな！
フォルテッシモで
行くわよ！
JAKUZURE NONON
BATTLEFIELD TRIP
KYOTO REGION
BRIGADE LEADER
What's up with this?
何これ？
（声Ａ）
ホッホッホッホッホ
ようこそ おいでやす
Welcome, warriors of the East.
あずまえびすの方々よ
Abekamo Academy,
which has stood for a thousand years
（声Ｂ）
いにしえの都に1000年続く—
この安倍賀茂(あべがも)学園こそ
京都守護の要どすえ
here in the ancient capital,
is the linchpin of Kyoto's defenses!
If you wish to avoid a painful death,
leave this place at once.
（声Ｃ）
痛い目に遭いとうなければ
とく去られよ
（声Ｄ）さもなくば百鬼夜行
魑魅魍魎(ちみもうりょう)の洗礼を受けますのんえ
Fail to do so, and you will be baptized
by a flood of demons and monsters.
（蛇崩）何 偉そうに言ってんの
Listen to you, trying to sound big!
1000年続く高校が
あるわけないじゃない
There aren't any schools that
have been around for a thousand years!
What are these things?
（文化部員Ａ）何だこいつら！
They're monsters!
（文化部員Ｂ）化け物だ！
They're gonna eat us!
（文化部員Ｃ）食われるぞ！
（玄武(げんぶ)）北の守護生徒…
Guardian Student of the North,
Genbu Tarou!
GUARDIAN
STUDENT
OF THE NORTH
GENBU
TAROU
Guardian Student of the South,
Suzaku Jirou!
（朱雀(すざく)）南の守護生徒…
GUARDIAN
STUDENT
OF THE SOUTH
SUZAKU
JIROU
Guardian Student of the East,
Seiryu Saburou!
（青龍(せいりゅう)）東の守護生徒…
SEIRYU SABUROU
GUARDIAN
STUDENT
OF THE EAST
Guardian Student of the West,
Byakko Shirou!
（白虎(びゃっこ)）西の守護生徒…
GUARDIAN
STUDENT
OF THE WEST
BYAKKO
SHIROU
Do you see?
This is the Divine Four Formation,
（玄武）見たか！
安倍賀茂学園
鉄壁の守り“四神(しじん)相応の陣”
Abekamo Academy's
impenetrable defense!
（朱雀）おはんら関東の野蛮人では
破ることはできまへんどすえ
You Kanto barbarians
cannot hope to defeat it!
What are you talking about?
（蛇崩）何 言ってんの
It's so obvious that these
monsters are all illusions!
どうせ こんな怪物たち
幻に決まってるんだから
Stay calm, everyone!
みんな落ち着いて！
こんなのただの心理攻撃よ
This is just a psychological attack!
What a fascinating bunch.
（犬牟田）面白い連中だね
Would you mind if I
fought them for a while?
（犬牟田）ちょっと相手を
させてもらっていいかな
うわっ 犬牟田
あんた大阪でしょ？ なぜここに？
Inumuta?! I thought you were in Osaka!
What are you doing here?
（犬牟田）驚くことはない
映研が投射してるホログラムだから
Don't be startled.
This is merely a hologram projected by the Film Club.
Armed Arts Club! Advance!
（犬牟田）武装美術部 前へ！
This is a non-Euclidean space creation ritual calculated by the Math Club.
これは数学部が計算した
非ユークリッド空間成立式
Art Club members, use this
as a basis for a Paradox Painting!
美術部諸君 これを基に
パラドックスペインティングだ！
Our EM field! Impossible!
（青龍）結界が 世も末どすえ
ESCHER
TOPOLOGY
ATTACK
An Escher Topology Attack.
What's that?
（蛇崩）何それ
The Divine Four Formation employs geomagnetism to
envelop this location in special electromagnetic waves,
（犬牟田）
四神相応の陣は地磁気を応用し
この場所を特殊な電磁波で包み—
人間の神経信号に
混乱をもたらすもの
thereby disrupting the
nerve signals of the human brain.
The picture they just drew altered this area's
phase space and disrupted its geomagnetism!
今 美術部が描いた絵で
この場所の位相空間を変化させ—
地磁気を混乱させた
結界を無効化したということだよ
In short, they have negated
the school's EM field!
全くわかんないけど
I didn't understand a word of that,
but I guess when it comes to
obnoxious jerks, it takes one to beat one.
嫌みな連中には
嫌みなヤツが効くってことね
（犬牟田）だったら ここからは
君の独壇場だね ほら
Then I guess this should be
your forte, should it not?
（玄武）
え〜い！ 面妖な片仮名を操る
ふらちなやからめ
You uncouth boors and your strange words!
You leave us no choice but to fight!
こうなれば戦うしかないどすえ！
（僧兵たち）どすえ！ どすえ！
This isn't my scene.
I'll leave them in your capable hands.
（犬牟田）
ああいうのは趣味じゃないんで
あとはよろしく
Thanks for nothing.
フン！ 勝手ばかり
よ〜し盛り上がっていくわよ！
Okay, let's get jazzed up!
Armed Wind Instrument Club!
（蛇崩）武装吹奏楽部！
Combat Orchestration!
コンバットオーケストレーション！
Pomp and Circumstance 'em!
曲は“威風堂々”！
（玄武）うぬぬ…
I'm surprised you made it this far,
you pitiful Honnouji Academy fleas.
NANIWA
KINMAN
HIGH
SCHOOL
STUDENT
COUNCIL
PRESIDENT
TAKARADA
KANEO
（モニター:宝多(たからだ)）よう来たな
本能字学園のどぐされども
I am the Naniwa Kinman High School
Student Council President, Takarada Kaneo!
難波金満(なにわきんまん)高校 生徒会長
宝多金男(かねお)や
You might've thought you were
hot stuff after Kobe and Kyoto,
神戸や京都では
ブイブイ言わしとるようやが
but you ain't so tough here in Osaka!
この大阪で
でかい面ができる思うなよ！
Well, well, you've heard
what happened in the other cities?
BATTLEFIELD
TRIP
OSAKA
REGION
BRIGADE
LEADER
SANAGEYAMA
UZU
（猿投山）ほう ほかの都市の
ウワサを知ってるのか
I thought we'd cut off
your information gateways.
情報網は遮断したはずだが
I hate to break it to ya,
あいにくこっちには—
大阪のおばはんっちゅう
強〜い味方がおってな
but I have powerful allies
in the form of Osakan grannies.
They'll spread gossip and rumors
in the blink of an eye.
ウワサは
あっちゅう間に広がるんや
ネットを封じても
人の口に戸は立てられへんで〜
Even if you lock down the net,
you can't stop gossipin' grandmas!
Now, listen close.
I'm gonna tell ya the rules of this town.
ええか！
この街のルール教えたる！
Osaka here is a merchant town!
この大阪は あきんどの街！
この街 回しとるんは銭や！
It's money that
makes this town go 'round!
Whoever has the most cash wins!
銭 持っとる者(もん)が
勝ちっちゅうこっちゃ！
Money? Philistine.
金(かね)だと 俗物が！
貴様のような—
We have come to bring down those
like you who reek of the old system
古い体制に染まりきっている
やからを駆逐し—
in order to create the new world order
that Kiryuuin Satsuki strives to achieve!
鬼龍院皐月様が目指す
新しき世界創造のために—
我々はここに来た！
You're adorable.
You naïve, naïve thing.
青いなぁ〜 青い青い
Don't start soapboxin' about society
until you learn how fearsome money can be.
銭の怖さを知らん者
世間を語るなかれや
今 貴様らの面 札束ではたいて
目覚まさせたるわ！
Time to make you wake up to reality
by smackin' you in the face with wads of cash!
All right, men! Let 'em have it!
野郎ども いてもうたれや！
We're gonna kill ya!
Guns?
（猿投山）銃だと？
（運動部員）お札です！
It's bills, sir!
They're shooting at us
with wads of bills as bullets!
（運動部員）
ヤツら札束を銃弾代わりにして
撃ってきています！
They're literally using money as a weapon!
ホントに金を武器にしています
I put my money where my mouth is!
（モニター:宝多）
わしは言動一致の男やねん
わかったらとっとと去(い)ね！
Get it? Then get lost!
Judging from the feel, these aren't
genuine Bank of Japan notes, are they?
（猿投山）この感触…
日本銀行券じゃないな
Counterfeit bills, huh?
偽札か！
They ain't counterfeit!
They're Takarada Bucks!
（モニター:宝多）
偽札ちゃうで 宝多札や
（猿投山）宝多札？
Takarada Bucks?
Exactly. They're redeemable paper currency.
（宝多）そのと〜おり だ換紙幣や
ウチら宝多財閥の名前は—
The word of the wealthy Takarada Conglomerate
is as good as gold here in Osaka.
大阪じゃ大金持ちで
とどろいてるでえ
借金まみれの国のお札より
価値があるんや
They have more value than
our debt-ridden national currency.
But I guess a northern Kanto hick
like you wouldn't understand any of that!
北関東の田舎者には
わからんやろなあ
How dare you!
貴様！
北関東をバカにすると
こんにゃく芋と一緒にすり潰すぞ！
If you go on mocking northern Kanto,
I'll grind you up with our konjac root harvest!
Not if we turn you jerks
into takoyaki first! Get 'em!
ほんなら おんどれらが
たこ焼きのたこになるんが先や
やったれい！
Armed Ping Pong Club!
Advance forward!
武装卓球部 前に！
（卓球部員たち）ピンポン！
Sumo Club, advance forward!
Sumo Stomp Attack!
続いて武装相撲部！
しこ攻撃だ！
（相撲部員たち）どすこい！
Armed Archery Club, Armed Track Club!
武装弓道部および武装陸上部
長距離投てき部隊！ 一斉攻撃！
Ultra long range squads! Salvo attack!
Not bad, kiddo!
（モニター:宝多）
おう やるなボンボン！
Now, storm the school building!
（猿投山）今だ！ 校舎に突入！
（運動部員たち）お〜！
Over my dead body! Force 'em back!
（モニター:宝多）
させるか　押し戻したれや！
You can stand against Ultima Uniforms?!
（猿投山）
極制服に対抗できるのか！
（モニター:宝多）ハハン！
鬼龍院だけが財閥やない
The Kiryuuins ain't the
only big players around here.
宝多財閥の銭の力
ナメんといてけ〜！
Don't underestimate the might of
the Takarada Conglomerate's money!
（兵站(へいたん)部員たち）えっほ えっほ
えっほ えっほ…
I'm gonna be heartbroken if I come all this way to Osaka
and all I get to do is this stupid ball bucket brigade!
（マコ）ハァ… せっかく
大阪まで来てるのに
こんなボール運びで終わっちゃ
切なすぎるよ
おっ！ あれは！
...Hey, that's...
It's the veritable symbol of Osaka!
Jumbo takoyaki sold by a street vendor!
あれこそは大阪の象徴
屋台のジャンボたこ焼き
It just isn't a trip to Osaka
without eating some of those!
あれを食べずして何の大阪行きよ！
OSAKA
ハッ！ でも お金がない！
But I've got no money!
I got dragged here without knowing why,
何だかよくわからないうちに
ここまで連れてこられたので—
私は今 一文無しのすっからかん！
so I'm flat broke right now! Penniless!
Boy, I sure wish somebody would
fire some money my way!
ハァ 誰かお金を
ばらまいてくれないか
There is! There's a guy who's
spreading money around with a gun!
いた！ お金を銃で
ばらまきまくってる人が！
ウハハ！
おんどりゃ 地獄に行きさらせ！
Bastard! I'm gonna send ya straight to Hell!
Not to Hell! I'm going straight to Heaven!
地獄じゃない！
私が行くのは極楽だ！
Go on, shoot me!
さあ撃ちなさい！
目先の欲に目がくらんだときの
満艦飾(まんかんしょく)マコをナメるな！
Don't you dare get between
Mankanshoku Mako and something she wants!
何や お前は！
Who the hell are you?
...No way...
（生徒）んな アホな！
（マコ）じゃ！
Bye!
Hey, gramps! Takoyaki, please!
I've got plenty of cash!
（マコ）おっちゃん たこ焼き！
金なら いくらでもあるで〜！
お〜！ あれこそは—
That's the Osaka-style okonomiyaki
that you eat with a spatula instead of chopsticks,
お箸で食わずにコテで食う
関西風お好み焼きに
ソース二度付け厳禁の串カツ！
キツネじゃなくてケツネうどん
and that's kushikatsu,
where you're not allowed to double dip!
And ketsune udon, not kitsune!
And best of all is the butaman,
the ikayaki, the negiyaki, and more!
午後一番には やっぱり豚マン
さらにイカ焼き ねぎ焼き その他
Now this is Osaka!
A Victory Road of food!
これぞ大阪！
食のビクトリーロードや！
You are all that remain!
（蟇郡）残るは貴君らのみ
Attack!
（蟇郡）やれ！
（砲弾の飛来音）
ハハハ！
ちょっとは びっくりしたか！
Sorry, did I surprise you?!
Here's a little something
we had the Russian mafia smuggle in.
ロシアマフィアから
こっそり密輸しとったんじゃい
I don't know 'bout no Ultima Uniforms,
極制服か何や知らんが
服で戦車に勝てるかいや
but can clothes stand up to a tank?!
Don't make me repeat myself!
何度も言わせるな！
Our ironclad rules will tear through
the armor of a mere tank as if it were paper!
戦車ごときの装甲は
鋼の規則で打ち砕く！
ぬう！
How's this?!
（大林）どうや！ 超最新型の…
The very latest iteration of Kobe's
specialty, composite meat armor!
KOBE SPECIALITY
COMPOSITE MEAT ARMOR
Your "ironclad rules" or whatever get swallowed up by that
beautiful Kobe beef marbling and melt away into nothing!
固いだけの貴様らの
校則とやらは—
神戸牛の霜降りに
飲み込まれてトロトロや！
さあ おとなしく降伏せえや 蟇郡
Now, be a good boy and surrender, Gamagoori.
Laughable! If you think
you can make me, let's see you try!
笑止！ やれるものなら
やってみろ！
くっ… だぼが　撃て！
Dumbass! Fire!
Fortified Disciplinary Unit, forward!
最強校則班 前へ！
Discipline!
（最強校則班員たち）手帳！
Oh crap! It's coming back!
（大林）うわっ！
なぜだ！ あった〜
That's hot! Hot!
（部下Ａ）熱い！
（部下Ｂ）熱い！ 焼ける！
Ow! It burns!
（部下Ｃ）肉が焼ける！
パクリ うまーい！
The meat's cooking! Yum!
It's so good!
These powered Godrobe patches certainly are something else.
（蟇郡）さすがは神衣による
パワーアップだ
Magnificent. Now, finish them!
すばらしい とどめを刺せ！
（最強校則班員たち）
大きい手帳！
So much for your final trump card.
（蟇郡）最後の切り札も
失ったようだな
Surrender peacefully, Oobayashi!
おとなしく降伏しろ！ 大林！
You! Matoi!
貴様！ 纏(まとい)
I came to get Senketsu back!
鮮血は返してもらった
Lovely! What a beautiful sound!
（蛇崩）
いいわ〜 とってもいい音！
神衣を付けてると
そんなにすてきな音が出せるんだ
With a Godrobe in our band,
we can play such beautiful music together!
（玄武）あわわ…
I guess that about does it.
（蛇崩）
ま こんなものかしら あ？
（流子）とうっ！
おりゃ〜！
Transfer student!
What are you doing here?!
転校生 なんでここに？
I don't have time to
mess around with you.
お前の相手をしてる暇はない
What's with that attitude?!
（蛇崩）何！ 何なの あの態度！
Why?
（生徒）なんでや〜！
（猿投山）貴様らなど竹刀で十分！
My bamboo sword is more
than enough for the likes of you!
It sounds like Gamagoori and Jakuzure have wrapped things up on their end.
（スピーカー:犬牟田）
蟇郡と蛇崩は
仕事を終えたみたいだよ
そちらはどうかな？
How are you coming along?
Most of the Kinman High
students have been dealt with.
（猿投山）金満高校生も
ほとんど壊滅状態だ
Tell Lady Satsuki that Osaka
will soon be under our control.
大阪制圧も間もなくだと
皐月様には伝えてくれ
（宝多）さ〜て それはどやろな？
I wouldn't be so sure about that!
Takarada?
（猿投山）宝多！
あんさん わての力
見くびっとるわ
You underestimate my power, friend.
The students aren't my only pawns!
生徒だけが わての手駒やない！
Thank you, come again!
（市民たち）毎度！
もうかりまっか？
How's business?! Not too bad!
ぼちぼちでんな！
You're making civilians
fight for you too, you bastard?
（猿投山）貴様！
一般市民まで戦わせるのか！
I am indeed.
そのとおり
でも一般市民いうんは
ちょっとちゃうわ
But it's not quite accurate
to call them civilians.
They're all Combat Citizens
who have been blinded by money.
みんな金に目くらんだ戦闘市民や
Everyone in this town
right now is just itchin' to fight!
今この街におるんは
みんな戦う気満々の連中や
They're tough!
手ごわいで
（マコ）
うほ〜！ あれが大阪の新名所
なにわスカイタワー
That's the newest Osakan spot,
the Naniwa Sky Tower!
Right! Let's climb it!
よ〜し登ろう！
When you see a high place,
you just get this irresistible urge to climb it!
高い所は訳もなく
登りたくなるもんね〜
うわっ！ ぎょえ〜！
いや〜！
How d'you like fightin' against Takarada Kaneo
and the "I Heart Osaka" Brigade?
宝多金男と
好っきやねん大阪軍団の攻撃は！
If you want to take Osaka,
you'll have to kill every last one of us!
大阪落としたかったら
皆殺しにしなはれ
In the end, the real thing that
motivates people is cold, hard cash!
人を動かすんは所詮 銭でっせ！
You "heart" it, eh?
どこが“好っきやねん”だ
What's the sense in
destroying your own city?
自分で自分の街を
破壊してどうする！
We'll just rebuild it afterward!
あとで造り直したらええんや
The contractors will love
all the extra work thrown their way!
そのほうが土建屋も
仕事が増えて喜ぶ
Okay, people!
さあみんな その男倒したら
100万宝多円やるで！
Kill that man, and I'll give you
a million Takarada Bucks!
Make him suffer!
いてもうたれや〜！
（宝多）さ〜て これだけの大勢
どないする気や？
So how are you gonna deal
with all these people, huh?
...That's—
（猿投山）あれは？
ん？ 何や この光は？
What's that light?
L-Lady Satsuki!
（猿投山）さ… 皐月様！
（マコ）ぎょえ〜！
ひえ〜！
...Ow...
あれ？
Huh?
（柔道部員）そりゃ！
（レスリング部員）おりゃ！
Hey, that's from Ryuuko's uniform, Senketsu!
（マコ）あれ？ それ
流子ちゃんの鮮血じゃ…
Hey, you're Mankanshoku, the second-year!
（柔道部員）あっ！
貴様は２年の満艦飾
（レスリング部員）
こんな所で何をしている？
What're you doing here?
You deserted in the face of the enemy
to go goofing around, didn't you?
（柔道部員）こいつ！
敵前逃亡して遊び回ってたな
What do you think the
Battlefield Trip is about, anyway?
（レスリング部員）襲学旅行を
何だと思っている！ 粛正だ！
Purge her!
（マコ）ヒ〜 ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry!
Ryuuko!
流子ちゃん！
I see you're taking things easy
and enjoying the sights of Osaka, Mako.
大阪観光とは のんきだな マコ
Boy, am I glad to see you, Ryuuko!
助かったよ 流子ちゃん！
うおっ！ 鮮血ちゃんが
バラバラになってる
Senketsu's all chopped to bits!
Yeah, but I'll get him back.
（流子）ああ だけど取り戻す
I'll take back every last piece
and make him good as new.
全部取り戻して
必ず鮮血を元に戻してやる
Oh, I get it, Ryuuko.
（マコ）そうか流子ちゃん
一張羅を取り戻しにここまで
You're going to all this trouble
'cause he's the only uniform you have.
（鮮血）あと１つだぞ 流子
There is only one left, Ryuuko.
Really? How are you feeling?
そうか どうだ調子は
Rather well.
You've changed, don't you think?
（鮮血）ああ ずいぶんいい
お前こそ違うんじゃないか？
How so?
（流子）何が？
The only part of me currently
supplying you with power is this scarf.
（鮮血）
今の私が流子に与えている力は
このスカーフ分だけだ
But even now, you're able to take down the
Ultima Uniforms augmented by my fragments in one strike.
それなのに私の一部を付けた
極制服の相手を瞬殺している
You've become even stronger
than before, don't you think?
以前よりも
強くなってるんじゃないか？
I'm getting stronger?
（流子）私が強くなってる？
It's because what you desire
is almost in reach!
（マコ）それは目先の欲に
目がくらんでんだよ
You're concentrating as hard as you can
on your desire to get Senketsu back to normal.
鮮血ちゃんを元に戻したいって
目先の欲に目がくらんで—
必死になってんだよ
I get the same way, but with money!
私だってお金のためなら
目がくらむよ！
Yeah, you concentrate pretty hard on that.
ああ！ マコの目の
くらみっぷりは筋金入りだ
Of course! You can't spell "concentrate" without "cent", after all!
（マコ）うん！
筋金入りも金のうちだよ！
（流子）よし 残り１つ
場所はわかるな？ 鮮血
Okay, one to go.
Can you tell where it is, Senketsu?
...Yes, I can. However...
（鮮血）ああ わかった だが…
（流子）どうした？
What is it?
The holder of the final fragment
is Kiryuuin Satsuki.
（鮮血）最後の１つを
持っているのは—
鬼龍院皐月だ
（流子）皐月だと？
（マコ）え〜っ！
Satsuki? Seriously?
Fine. I'll get you back,
no matter who I have to face.
わかった 誰が持っていようが
お前は必ず取り戻す！
But in my current condition,
I cannot activate Life Fiber Synchronize mode.
（鮮血）しかし今の私では
人衣(じんい)一体に変身できないぞ
How do you intend to
fight an opponent like Satsuki?
皐月相手にどう戦う？
Don't worry. I'll pick up the slack.
（流子）心配すんな
その分は私が補う
I'm not the usual Matoi Ryuuko right now.
今の私は ただの纏流子じゃない
I'm concentrating everything I have,
now that my goal is almost within reach.
目先の欲に目がくらんでる
纏流子だ
Isn't that right, Mako?
（流子）そうだな マコ
（マコ）うん！
Yeah!
（鮮血）流子
...Ryuuko...
I'm coming for you, Kiryuuin Satsuki!
（流子）待ってろ 鬼龍院皐月！
Before the bell rings
chime ga naru mae ni
I sneak out of school
kugurinuketa
Avoiding the adults' vacant stares
otonatachi no haiiro no me
The pointless conversations
tawai no nai kaiwa
Keep going on and on
togirenu mama
As I walk down the slope
sakamichi wo kudatteku
I have nothing to do
nani wo suru demo naku
And nowhere to go
yuku ate sae mo naku
Right now, all I do
tada atashi ima wa ne
Is ignore any and all warnings
donna chuukoku mo mimi wo surinukeru
Because I still want to be free
mada mada suki ni sasete
I'm sorry, but it's not like me
gomen ne e ni kaita you na
To be an exemplary student
yuutosei wa rashiku nai wa
So I undo two of my shirt buttons
shirt no button wo futatsu hazushite
And take the back alley
rojiura no nukemichi
A path of mysterious sweet temptation
amai yuuwaku wa michi
Some things I've kept hidden from everyone
dare ni mo mada hanashite nai
But tonight, I will reveal my secrets to you
atashi no himitsu wo kon'ya oshiete ageru
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
（鮮血）金が物言う街 大阪
銭クレイジー 大阪
Osaka, a town where money talks!
OSAKA
Cash-crazy Osaka!
バラバラになった神衣鮮血を求めて
流子も参入する
SCATTERED
In search of her scattered Godrobe Senketsu,
Ryuuko dives into the fray!
GODROBE SENKETSU
果たして神衣鮮血は復活するのか
私のことだが
IN THE END
Will Godrobe Senketsu be revived in the end?! Oh, right, that's me.
GODROBE SENKETSU
THAT'S ME
Next time on KILL la KILL,
"Don't Stop Me Now"!
次回 キルラキル
「どうにも とまらない」
EPISODE 15
DON'T STOP ME NOW